Friends, let me introduce myself.
Amigos, dejen que me presente.
Peltzer's the name. Rand Peltzer.
Me llamo Peltzer. Rand Peltzer.
That's me there on the corner.
Soy ése de la esquina.
I'm an inventor.
Soy inventor.
And I have a story to tell.
Tengo una historia que contar.
I know. Who hasn't got a story?
Lo sé. Todos tenemos historias.
Well, nobody's got a story like this one.
Pero nadie tiene una como ésta.
Nobody.
Nadie.
It all started here in Chinatown.
Todo empezó aquí, en Chinatown.
I was trying to move a little merchandise...
Trataba de vender alguna mercancía...
...maybe find a present for my kid.
...y encontrar un regalo para mi hijo.
I tried this one place.
Probé en una de esas tiendas.
Wait a minute.
Un momento.
What's down here?
¿Qué hay ahí abajo?
This is it.
Es aquí.
This is your grandfather's store?
¿Ésta es la tienda de tu abuelo?
Come on.
Vamos.
No wonder you gotta drag people in off the street.
Por eso tienes que arrastrar a los clientes aquí.
Go ahead, mister. Look around.
Adelante, señor. Eche un vistazo.
See if there's something you like.
A ver si hay algo que le guste.
Are these things real?
¿Son auténticos?
I told you, everything's real.
Se lo dije, todo es auténtico.
You do have interesting artifacts here...
Tiene cachivaches interesantes...
...but there's one thing you don't have.
...pero hay algo que no tiene.
And what's that?
¿Qué es?
Let me show you. I'm an inventor. I made this.
Soy inventor. He ideado esto.
The Bathroom Buddy. The invention of the century.
El Compinche del Aseo. El invento del siglo.
It eliminates the need to carry heavy luggage when you travel.
Con él no hace falta llevar tanto equipaje en los viajes.
You got yourself your shaving mirror...
Consta de un espejo para afeitarse...
...your toothbrush, a toothpick. You got toenail clippers...
...cepillo de dientes, un palillo, y un cortauñas...
...a nail file...
...una lima de uñas...
...and you got yourself a dental mirror.
...y un espejo dental.
This is gonna revolutionize traveling.
Esto revolucionará los viajes.
Let's just say, for the sake of argument...
Le voy a poner un ejemplo...
...that you're on a bus, a plane or a train.
...usted va en autobús, avión o tren.
You forgot to brush your teeth.
Y ha olvidado lavarse los dientes.
You got yourself a bad case of dragon breath.
Y tiene aliento de dragón.
Bad breath.
Mal aliento.
What do you do?
¿Qué hace?
No problem, friend. All you do is...
Ningún problema, amigo. Simplemente...
...you take your toothbrush out...
...saca su cepillo...
...and you push this button.
...y aprieta este botón.
That's absolutely no problem.
No pasa nada.
Cleans up easily.
Se limpia fácilmente.
What I'd like to do, sir, is give you my card.
Me gustaría darle mi tarjeta, señor.
Rand Peltzer. "Fantastic Ideas for a Fantastic World. "
Rand Peltzer. "Ideas Geniales para un Mundo Genial".
I make the illogical logical.
Hago lógico lo ilógico.
I can get you these.
Puedo traerle más.
I can get them by the dozen if you'd like.
Puedo traerle docenas si quiere.
What do you think?
¿Qué le parece?
Where's that coming from?
¿Qué es ese ruido?
What is that?
¿Qué es?
Mogwai.
Mogwai.
What's he doing?
¿Qué hace?
Singing.
Canta.
He does that sometimes.
Lo hace a veces.
I gotta have him. He's incredible.
Lo quiero. Es increíble.
Tell you what I'll do.
Mire.
- I'll give you $100 for him. No.
Le doy 100$.
I've gotta have him. It's a present for my son for Christmas.
Es el regalo de Navidad de mi hijo.
It's what I've been looking for.
Es lo que he estado buscando.
I've been everywhere. I'll give you $200.
He mirado en todas partes. Le daré 200.
That's $200!
¡200!
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Mogwai not for sale.
Mogwai no está en venta.
You said everything here was for sale.
Dijiste que todo estaba en venta.
Grandfather!
¡Abuelo!
With mogwai comes much responsibility.
Mogwai conlleva mucha responsabilidad.
I cannot sell him at any price.
No puedo venderlo a ningún precio.
Wait outside. I'll be right out.
Espere fuera. Ahora salgo.
Just go.
Salga.
Okay, mister, here it is.
Bien, señor, aquí está.
What about your grandfather?
¿Qué dirá tu abuelo?
Forget what he said. He's crazy. We need the money.
Olvídelo. Está loco. Necesitamos el dinero.
Do you want it or not?
¿Lo quiere o no?
I want it.
Lo quiero.
There's three rules you've gotta follow.
Hay tres reglas que debe seguir.
What kind of rules?
¿Qué reglas?
Keep him out of the light.
Que no le dé la luz.
He hates bright light, especially sunlight.
Odia la luz brillante, sobre todo la del sol.
It'll kill him.
Eso lo mataría.
And keep him away from water. Don't get him wet.
Que no le toque el agua. Que no se moje.
But the most important rule, the rule you can never forget...
Pero la regla más importante, la que no debe olvidar...
...no matter how much he cries or how much he begs...
...no importa cuánto llore o suplique...
...never, never feed him after midnight. Got it?
...nunca le dé comida después de medianoche.
Sure. Whatever you say.
Lo que tú digas.
Thanks. And have a merry Christmas.
Gracias. Y Feliz Navidad.
You're rolling with Rockin' Ricky Rialto...
¡Estás con Rockin' Ricky Rialto...
...the voice of Kingston Falls, U.S.A.!
...la voz de Kingston Falls, EE.UU.!
Alex...
Hola, Alex...
Getting close to Christmas.
La Navidad se acerca.
You'll get stuck with a lot of trees again.
Otra vez con un montón de árboles.
I thought I'd see you about now. Ow!
Sabía que vendrías por estas fechas.
What the hell is this?
¿Qué demonios es eso?
What are you doing in there?
¿Qué haces ahí?
Don't ask.
No pregunte.
Alex, I came to get my tree.
Alex, vengo a por mi árbol.
Pete, take that tree to Mr. Anderson's truck.
Pete, llévale ese árbol a la camioneta.
What do you say, Alex?
¿Qué dices, Alex?
You can spare one for the sheriff's station.
¿Donarás uno a la oficina del sheriff?
I paid for mine, Frank.
Yo he pagado el mío, Frank.
Billy, you need a jump?
Billy, ¿te ayudo?
No, thanks, Mr. Futterman. I'm late for work as it is.
No, gracias, Mr. Futterman. Ya llego tarde.
These goddamn foreign cars always freeze up on you.
Estos coches extranjeros siempre se congelan.
You don't find American machinery doing that.
A los americanos no les pasa.
See that plow?
¿Ves la excavadora?
Hasn't given me a day's trouble in 15 years.
No me ha dado un problema en 15 años.
You know why? Kentucky Harvester.
¿Por qué? Kentucky Harvester.
It ain't some foreign piece of crap. That's a Kentucky Harvester.
No es una basura extranjera. Es una Kentucky Harvester.
If I wanna keep my job, I should be going now.
Debo irme si quiero conservar mi puesto.
How's your comic strip coming?
¿Cómo va tu cómic?
I expect to see you in the funnies with "Smilin' Jack," "Li'I Abner. "
Espero verlo pronto junto al Guerrero del Antifaz.
They don't run those comics anymore.
Esos cómics ya no se llevan.
They don't?
¿Ah, no?
Come on, Barn.
Vamos, Barn.
Say hello to your wife, okay?
Recuerdos a su esposa.
So long, Billy.
Hasta luego, Billy.
Goddamn foreign cars.
Malditos coches extranjeros.
Hey, doctor.
Hola, doctor.
Morning, Billy.
Buenos días, Billy.
Get in there and be quiet.
Métete ahí y no hagas ruido.
- You just made it. - Again.
- Has llegado por los pelos. - Otra vez.
Will you sign this petition?
¿Me firmas esta petición?
Sure. What's it for?
Claro. ¿Para qué es?
To declare Dorry's pub a landmark.
Declarar el bar de Dorry de interés histórico.
Mrs. Deagle's trying to take his lease away.
La Sra. Deagle quiere echarle.
His too?
¿A él también?
Yeah, she says it's a dive, a public nuisance.
Sí, dice que es un antro, una molestia para la sociedad.
That's where my dad proposed to my mom.
Allí se declaró mi padre a mi madre.
That's where everybody's dad proposed to their mom. Cross your "T."
Todos nuestros padres se declararon allí.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Good morning, Mrs. Deagle.
Buenos días, Sra. Deagle.
What's good about it?
¿Qué tienen de buenos?
Klutz!
¡Klutz!
Watch it, watch it!
¡Cuidado, cuidado!
40, 60, 80...
40, 60, 80...
Two hundred. Thank you.
200. Gracias.
- Mrs. Deagle? - What?
- ¿Sra. Deagle? - ¿Qué?
I just wanted you to know that Joe got another job.
Sólo decirle que Joe encontró otro trabajo.
My husband, Joe Harris.
Mi marido, Joe Harris.
And I've taken up some sewing.
Y yo coso ropa.
What are you trying to tell me?
¿Qué intenta decirme?
Neither of us will be paid for two weeks.
No cobraremos hasta dentro de dos semanas.
Couldn't you get Mr. Corben...
Si el Sr. Corben...
...to give us a little more time?
...nos diese más tiempo.
Mrs. Harris...
Sra. Harris...
...the bank and I have the same purpose in life...
...el banco y yo tenemos el mismo objetivo...
...to make money.
...ganar dinero.
Not to support a lot of...
No mantener a unos...
...deadbeats.
...muertos de hambre.
Mrs. Deagle, it's Christmas!
¡Sra. Deagle, es Navidad!
Now you know what to ask Santa for, don't you?
Ya sabe qué pedirle a Papá Noel, ¿no?
Mommy, I'm hungry.
Mamá, tengo hambre.
Yes, honey. So am I.
Sí, cielo. Yo también.
This is what's left of my imported Bavarian snowman.
Esto es mi muñeco de nieve de importación.
Your dog broke it this morning!
¡Tu perro lo rompió esta mañana!
I'm terribly sorry.
Lo siento mucho.
Tell me how much I owe you...
Dígame cuánto le debo...
I don't want money.
No quiero dinero.
I want your dog.
Quiero tu perro.
Barney?
¿Barney?
Give him to me.
Dámelo.
I'll take him to the kennel. They'll put him to sleep.
Lo llevaré a la perrera. Allí lo dormirán.
It'll be quick and painless, compared to what I could do to him.
Será rápido, comparado con lo que le haría yo.
What could you do?
¿Qué le harías?
I'll catch the beast myself.
Agarraría a esa bestia.
Then he'll get what he deserves.
Y le daría su merecido.
A slow, painful death.
Una muerte lenta y dolorosa.
Maybe I'll put him in my spin dryer on high heat.
Quizá lo metería en la secadora a toda potencia.
That'd do it.
Sería suficiente.
Barney, will you get off of her?
¡Barney, déjala!
My dear lady, are you all right?
Señora, ¿está usted bien?
I have a very weak heart. I can't stand a shock like that!
Un shock muy fuerte para mi débil corazón.
What is that dog doing in here?
¿Qué hace aquí este perro?
This is a bank, not a pet store.
Esto es un banco.
Very good, Gerald.
Muy bien, Gerald.
He wouldn't hurt you.
No le haría daño.
Excuses, excuses. You're just like your father.
Excusas, excusas. Eres idéntico a tu padre.
I've listened to his excuses for 10 years, the loser!
He aguantado sus excusas durante 10 años, ¡perdedor!
As for you, you mangy cur...
Y tú, chucho sarnoso...
...I'll get you...
...te agarraré...
...when you least expect it!
...¡cuando menos lo esperes!
Oh, my heart!
¡Oh, mi corazón!
I must apologize for this most unusual...
Acepte mis disculpas por este insólito...
You putz.
Patán.
The old bat never looked better.
La vieja bruja queda muy bien.
It's great. You're doing fine.
Genial. Lo haces muy bien.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Hello, Gerald.
Hola, Gerald.
If it isn't Captain Clip-on.
Si es el Capitán Grapas.
Guess who almost applied for unemployment today?
Adivina quién ha estado a punto de perder su trabajo.
- I give up. - You.
- Me rindo. - Tú.
But Mr. Corben had second thoughts.
Pero el Sr. Corben se lo pensó.
He gets so sentimental about the holidays.
Se pone tan sentimental en Navidad.
Imagine that.
Supongo.
I would've fired you in a second.
Yo te habría despedido.
Merry Christmas to you too.
Feliz Navidad a ti también.
Excuse me, Mr. Jones.
Disculpe, Sr. Jones.
Hey, Peltzer.
Eh, Peltzer.
Look, I'm a junior vice president at 23.
Tengo 23 años y soy vicepresidente.
By the time I'm 25, I'm gonna have Mr. Corben's job.
A los 25, estaré en el puesto del Sr. Corben.
By the time I'm 30, I'll be a millionaire.
A los 30, seré millonario.
Look at you.
Mírate.
You're practically supporting your whole family.
Mantienes a toda tu familia.
The world's changing.
El mundo cambia.
You gotta change with it. You gotta be tough.
Tienes que cambiar con él, ser duro.
Tough? And no one's tougher than you, Ger?
¿Duro? Eres el más duro, ¿eh, Ger?
Don't call me that. My name's Gerald.
No me llames así. Mi nombre es Gerald.
Can I get you a drink?
¿Qué vas a tomar?
Give me a vodka martini. Shake, don't stir.
Un Martini con vodka. Agítalo.
You work here?
¿Trabajas aquí?
Weeknights so Dorry doesn't have to pay an extra waitress.
De noche, así Dorry se ahorra una camarera.
That's great.
Qué bien.
Yeah, that's swell, if you like working for nothing.
Sí, si te gusta trabajar por nada.
Two more rounds for the pool table, on the house.
Dos rondas más para aquella mesa, paga la casa.
You haven't seen my new apartment.
No has visto mi nuevo piso.
I haven't seen your old apartment.
No he visto tu viejo piso.
We're talking cable. Can we have dinner tomorrow night?
Tenemos TV por cable. ¿Cenamos mañana?
I'm working.
Trabajo.
Why don't you tell Dorry you're sick? He can't dock your pay.
Dile a Dorry que estás enferma. Para lo que te paga...
Billy, is that you?
Billy, ¿eres tú?
Yeah, Mom, it's me.
Sí, mamá, soy yo.
I'm in the kitchen.
Estoy en la cocina.
Merry Christmas!
¡Feliz Navidad!
- Hi, Mom. - Hi, sweetie.
- Hola, mamá. - Hola, cielo.
Do you need any help?
¿Te ayudo?
Yeah, you could do the eggs.
Sí, bate los huevos.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Dad's machines work so well the first couple of weeks, then...
Los inventos de papá funcionan las dos primeras semanas...
Use the sink.
Hazlo en el fregadero.
Is something wrong?
¿Te pasa algo?
No, it's a sad movie.
No, es una película triste.
How was your day?
¿Cómo te ha ido?
It was fine.
Bien.
Come on, what is it? What's wrong?
Vamos, ¿qué pasa? ¿Qué ocurre?
Mrs. Deagle called again this afternoon.
La Sra. Deagle ha venido otra vez.
Let's not talk about it now. Don't say anything to Dad.
No hablemos de eso. No le digas nada a papá.
Fine with me.
Por mí, bien.
Hi, sweetheart!
¡Hola, cariño!
- Welcome home. - Hey, Dad.
- Bienvenido a casa. - Hola, papá.
I'm glad you're back. How was the trip?
Me alegro de verte. ¿Qué tal el viaje?
It was great.
Fantástico.
The Miracle Company, who has the Kitchen Companion...
La Compañía Milagro...
...might be interested in the Bathroom Buddy.
...podría estar interesada en el Compinche del Aseo.
Great!
¡Estupendo!
- Thanks! - You'll like this.
- ¡Gracias! - Te gustará.
What is it? A birdcage?
¿Qué es? ¿Una jaula?
No, don't shake it. Open it now. It won't wait till Christmas.
No, lo muevas. Ábrelo. No puede esperar a Navidad.
It's a puppy, isn't it?
Es un cachorro, ¿no?
Yeah, I can tell.
Seguro.
It's a new car.
Es un coche nuevo.
- Honey, would you dim the lights? - Sure.
- Baja las luces. - Claro.
Dim the lights? Does it glow in the dark?
¿Brilla en la oscuridad?
It's important. Trust me.
Es importante. Confía en mí.
Go ahead, open it.
Adelante, ábrelo.
What is it?
¿Qué es?
It's your new pet.
Tu nueva mascota.
Come on, Barney. Be a good dog.
Vamos, Barney. Sé buen chico.
You're kidding.
Bromeas.
Dad, it's really neat.
Papá es perfecto.
Where'd you get this?
¿Dónde lo compraste?
Some little junk store in Chinatown.
En una tienducha de Chinatown.
- Can I pick him up? - Sure, go ahead. Just be careful.
¿Puedo cogerlo?
- You gotta be gentle. - I will.
- Con delicadeza. - Sí.
I hope he's housebroken.
Espero que esté domesticado.
Isn't he cute?
Es una monada.
Has it got a name?
¿Tiene nombre?
Mogwai.
Mogwai.
Some Chinese word. I just call him...
Un nombre chino. Yo lo llamo...
...Gizmo. He seems to like it.
...Gizmo. Parece que le gusta.
Look up here a minute.
Mira hacia aquí.
We're getting our picture taken.
Nos van a sacar una foto.
Smile.
Sonríe.
Ready?
¿Listo?
One, two, three...
Un, dos, tres...
No, no. Bright light!
¡Luz brillante!
What happened?
¿Qué ha pasado?
He hates bright lights.
Odia la luz brillante.
There's some important things I forgot to tell you.
Olvidé decirte unas reglas importantes.
Number one, he hates bright lights. You gotta keep him out of the sunlight.
Uno, odia la luz brillante. No debe darle la luz del sol.
Sunlight will kill him.
Lo mataría.
Number two, keep him away from water.
Dos, mantenerlo alejado del agua.
Don't give him any water to drink. Whatever you do, don't give him a bath.
No le des agua para beber. Ni se te ocurra bañarlo.
And the most important thing...
Y lo más importante...
...don't ever feed him after midnight.
...nunca le des de comer después de medianoche.
Looks like you hurt yourself.
Te has herido.
Light bright! Light bright!
¡Luz brillante!
Just sit down there and don't fall off, okay?
Siéntate ahí y no te caigas, ¿bien?
I'll get you fixed up in no time.
Te curaré enseguida.
All right.
A ver.
Hold still.
No te muevas.
Sorry. Sorry.
Lo siento. Lo siento.
Try not to move so much, okay?
No te muevas tanto.
Good night, Giz. I'll see you in the morning.
Buenas noches, Giz. Hasta mañana.
I got a tree!
¡Traigo el árbol!
Oh, Christ!
¡Oh, vaya!
Billy!
¡Billy!
I just brought in your Christmas tree.
Les traigo el árbol de Navidad.
What happened?
¿Qué ha pasado?
Slight problem with the Peltzer Peeler-Juicer.
Un pequeño problema con el exprimidor Peltzer.
I thought your dad fixed it.
Creí que tu padre lo había arreglado.
I thought so too.
Yo también.
You should just buy orange juice in cartons. It's a lot easier.
Deberías comprarlo en tetra-brik. Es más fácil.
See, it works.
Mira, funciona.
I had to come. So I see.
- Tenía que venir. - Ya lo veo.
Now I can see. It takes...
Ahora veo que hay que ser...
...a certain kind of guy.
...un hombre especial.
And that guy needs a certain kind of dame.
Y ese hombre necesita una mujer especial.
It's no problem, Pete. Leave it up here.
No te preocupes, Pete. Déjalo ahí.
What'll you tell him?
¿Qué le dirás?
I'll just tell him a bunch of bikers stole it from me on my way home.
Le diré que unos motociclistas me lo robaron.
Wow! The Hooded Menace. Issue number one!
¡Guau! Hood y su pandilla. ¡El primer número!
Pretty neat, huh?
Genial, ¿eh?
Where'd you get it?
¿Dónde lo has conseguido?
Dr. Fantasy's, I think.
En la tienda Dr. Fantasía.
- What's that? - Come here. I'll show you.
¿Qué es eso?
This is my new pet. My dad gave him to me.
Mi nueva mascota. Regalo de mi padre.
Neat! What's his name?
¡Guau! ¿Cómo se llama?
His name's Gizmo. Hi, Giz.
Gizmo. Hola, Giz.
He's a mogwai.
Es un mogwai.
Cute!
¡Qué mono!
Blink your eyes.
Guiña los ojos.
Go like that. Can you do that?
Así. ¿Puedes?
Watch. Maybe he'll sing.
Mira, a lo mejor canta.
Come on, Giz. Let's go over to the table.
Venga, Giz. Vamos a la mesa.
I'll be careful.
Ya voy con cuidado.
There we go.
Allá vamos.
Gee, Billy, where can I get one of those?
Billy, ¿dónde puedo conseguir uno?
I don't know. This is the only one I've ever seen.
No sé. Es el único que he visto.
Can I hold him?
¿Puedo cogerlo?
Sure. I don't see why not. He seems to like you.
Claro. ¿Por qué no? Le caes bien.
Great! Thanks a lot.
¡Genial! Gracias.
Sorry.
Lo siento.
What was in that jar?
¿Qué había en el frasco?
Nothing! Just water!
¡Nada! ¡Sólo agua!
Why is he making that noise?
¿Por qué se pone así?
What is it?
¿Qué es eso?
I don't know.
No lo sé.
Is it alive?
¿Está vivo?
One, two, three, four, five new ones.
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco más.
Now can I have one?
¿Puedo quedarme uno?
I don't know.
No lo sé.
Look, that one's got a cute stripe on its head.
Ése tiene un mechón en la cabeza.
Isn't that incredible, Pete?
¿No es increíble, Pete?
Yeah, great.
Sí, genial.
Don't you think this...? This is incredible!
¿No crees que es...? ¡Increíble!
Oh, it is neat.
Genial.
I'm serious. It's neat.
En serio. Es genial.
Gizmo, what's the matter?
Gizmo, ¿qué pasa?
- There's something I should tell you. - Look.
- Debo decirte algo. - Mira.
You're familiar with the Bathroom Buddy?
¿Te acuerdas del Compinche del Aseo?
I have made an improvement.
Lo he mejorado.
Watch this.
Mira esto.
Now, let's say you're late for the big meeting.
Imagina que llegas tarde a una reunión importante.
It's really important.
Muy importante.
You're on your way. You reach up. You forgot to shave.
Vas de camino y te acuerdas de que no te has afeitado.
What're you gonna do? Under normal circumstances...
¿Qué haces? En circunstancias normales...
...you are in trouble.
...sería un problema.
But not if you have the Bathroom Buddy.
Pero no, si tienes el Compinche del Aseo.
Watch this.
Mira esto.
What do you think?
¿Qué te parece?
That's pretty neat.
Fantástico.
What's this button?
¿Qué es ese botón?
- Sorry, Dad. - It's okay.
- Perdón, papá. - No pasa nada.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
It's not your fault. I'm working on that. I haven't finished that.
No es culpa tuya. Aún no está perfeccionado.
I came up here because there's a problem with the mogwai.
He subido porque hay un problema con el mogwai.
Yeah, what's that?
¿Qué problema?
It multiplies with water.
Se multiplica con el agua.
Do you see what I mean?
¿Lo ves?
I don't believe that.
No puedo creerlo.
All that from water? They got wet?
¿Sólo con agua?
Plain water.
Agua corriente.
It's funny. The new ones aren't like Gizmo.
Los nuevos no son como Gizmo.
The striped one seems to be the leader.
El del mechón parece el líder.
You know what?
¿Sabes qué?
I'll bet every kid in America would like one of these.
Apuesto a que todos los niños querrían uno.
They might replace the dog as the family pet.
Sería la nueva mascota familiar.
Think about it.
Imagínate.
The Peltzer Pet.
La mascota Peltzer.
This could really be the big one.
Ésta sí que sería buena.
Barney, who did this to you?
Barney, ¿quién te ha hecho eso?
Hold on, I'll get you down.
Espera, ahora te bajo.
Stay still.
No te muevas.
Poor dog. Another minute and he would've been a dog-sicle.
Pobrecito. Un poco más y acabas hecho puré.
All I know is that I'm positive that I closed and locked the door.
Estoy seguro de que cerré la puerta.
How else did she get to him?
¿Cómo pudo atraparlo ella?
We can't point any fingers, not even at Mrs. Deagle.
No podemos acusar a nadie, ni siquiera a la Sra. Deagle.
She's been threatening him. She'd love to get her hands on him.
Lo amenazó. Le encantaría ponerle las manos encima.
We don't have proof. We can't even find footprints leading up to the house.
No tenemos pruebas. No hay ni huellas en dirección a la casa.
I'm gonna take Barney to your grandmother's.
Llevaré a Barney a casa de la abuela.
Take him there on the way to the convention, pick him up on the way home.
Lo llevaré al ir a la convención, lo recogeré al volver.
He'll be here for Christmas. It'll be all right.
Estará aquí para Navidad. Todo irá bien.
I don't think we can drink this.
Esto no se puede beber.
Why not?
¿Por qué no?
What's wrong with this?
¿Qué tiene de malo?
Is that a mogwai?
¿Es un mogwai?
Yeah, I'm gonna have Mr. Hanson check it out.
Sí, quiero que el Sr. Hanson lo examine.
And all of a sudden, there were five new ones like this one.
Y de repente, había cinco como éste.
Now watch this.
Ahora mire esto.
Can I keep one of these here, run some tests on him?
¿Puedo quedarme alguno? Le haré pruebas.
I think I can spare one.
Sí, creo que me sobran.
This is some Christmas, Katie, I'll tell you.
Vaya unas Navidades, Katie, de verdad.
First the old bat closes the factory, and now it's my goddamn plow.
Primero la vieja bruja cierra la fábrica, y ahora la maldita excavadora.
Mr. Futterman, guess what? It's time to go home now.
Sr. Futterman, adivine. Es hora de ir a casa.
- How about one more beer? - No, it's late.
- Quiero otra cerveza. - No, es tarde.
One more beer, I'll help you clean up.
Una más, y te ayudo a limpiar.
No, thanks, though. It'll be okay.
No, gracias. Está bien.
- It'll be okay. - It will not be okay.
- Está bien. - No está bien.
I brought my plow in for a tune-up and found it loaded with foreign parts.
Llevé la excavadora a arreglar y las piezas eran extranjeras.
I mean, everything. Gaskets, pistons, spark plugs.
Todas. Juntas, pistones, bujías.
All of it's foreign.
Todo extranjero.
Going home?
¿Vuelve a casa?
Gremlins!
¡Gremlins!
You gotta watch out for foreigners.
Cuidado con los extranjeros.
They plant gremlins in their machinery.
Ponen gremlins en las máquinas.
The same gremlins brought down our planes in the big one.
Los gremlins que derribaron nuestros aviones en la guerra.
That's right.
Eso es.
World War II.
La Guerra Mundial.
Good old...
La grande...
...W- W-I-I.
...la Segunda.
They're still shipping them over here.
Nos los siguen enviando.
They put them in the cars, the TV.
En los coches, las teles.
They put them in the radios you stick in your ears.
En las radios con auriculares.
They put them in the watches. Little teeny gremlins.
Hasta en los relojes. Gremlins menuditos.
It's not a good idea that you drive. Why don't you walk home?
No puede conducir así. ¿Por qué no vuelve a pie?
You know, Katie, I think maybe I'll walk home.
¿Sabes, Katie? Creo que iré andando.
- Good. - It's a nice night.
Muy bien.
- Good night, kids. - Good night.
Buenas noches, chicos.
Gremlins.
Gremlins.
That was really good, the way you handled Mr. Futterman.
Te las has arreglado muy bien con el Sr. Futterman.
I'm used to it.
Estoy acostumbrada.
He's been like that ever since he lost his job.
Está así desde que le despidieron.
He's like a lot of people around here. He just wants somebody to listen.
Hay muchos en su situación. Sólo quiere que alguien le escuche.
Especially around the holidays.
Especialmente en Navidad.
Why is that?
¿Por qué?
It's when a lot of people get really depressed.
En esta época mucha gente se deprime.
I always thought everyone was happy during the holidays, no matter what.
Pensaba que todo el mundo era feliz en Navidad, a pesar de todo.
Most people are, but some aren't.
La mayoría sí, pero algunos no.
While everybody else opens up presents, they're opening up their wrists.
Mientras los demás abren regalos, ellos se abren las venas.
Cheery thought.
Vaya humor.
It's true. The suicide rate's always the highest around the holidays.
Es verdad. Los suicidios aumentan en estas fiestas.
Now I'm depressed.
Ahora estoy deprimido.
Do you ever get depressed on Christmas?
¿Te deprimes en Navidad?
I don't celebrate Christmas.
No celebro la Navidad.
Are you Hindu or something?
¿Eres hindú o algo?
No, I just don't like to.
No, simplemente no me gusta.
What's not to like? I mean, it's a lot of fun.
¿Qué no te gusta? Es divertido.
God!
¡Dios!
Say you hate Thanksgiving, and nobody cares.
Si odias Acción de Gracias, no importa.
But say you hate Christmas, everybody makes you feel like you're a leper.
Pero si odias la Navidad, te tratan como a un leproso.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
- Lo siento. - No pasa nada.
I'm sorry. I'm just a little tired and cranky.
Perdona. Estoy un poco cansada y nerviosa.
Thanks for walking me home.
Gracias por acompañarme.
No problem.
No tiene importancia.
- Good night.
Buenas noches.
I was just wondering, do you get any free nights off from Dorry's?
Me preguntaba si tienes libre alguna noche en el bar de Dorry.
Thursdays.
Los jueves.
Thursdays, yeah.
Los jueves, bien.
Because I was just wondering...
Porque me preguntaba si...
...if you're free this Thursday night, maybe you'd like to go out on a date...
...si no tienes planes este jueves, quizá te gustaría salir...
...with me?
...conmigo.
I'd love to.
Me encantaría.
Well, that's great!
¡Genial!
We can talk about it on the phone and kind of...
Ya hablaremos por teléfono y...
...square everything away.
...nos pondremos de acuerdo.
Good night, Billy.
Buenas noches, Billy.
Hey there.
Hola.
Give me your arm, boy. Come here, come on.
Dame el brazo, chico. Vamos, vamos.
Give me your arm. No, this is not gonna hurt.
Dame el brazo. No, no te dolerá.
This isn't gonna hurt.
No te dolerá.
Not a big guy like you. Come on.
Eres todo un hombre. Venga.
There you go. See, that's not so bad. Come on.
Allá voy. Ves, no es para tanto.
Good, good. Oh, that's good.
Bien, bien. Muy bien.
Just a little blood test, pal. You'll never miss it.
Sólo es un análisis de sangre. No la extrañarás.
They're like huge seedpods!
¡Son como semillas gigantes!
- Having fun? - Fun!
- ¿Es divertido? - ¡Divertido!
Pretty neat, huh?
Genial, ¿eh?
Neat!
¡Genial!
How about shutting up for a change, okay?
¿Por qué no se callan para variar?
I already fed you.
Ya les he dado de comer.
Well, it's not 12:00 yet.
Bueno, aún no son las 12:00.
All right. Keep an eye on them, Giz. I'll be back in a second.
Está bien. Vigílalos, Giz. Enseguida vuelvo.
Here we go.
Aquí tienen.
Now maybe you guys will be quiet.
Y ahora a ver si se callan.
You guys are really hungry.
Tenían mucha hambre.
Giz, you want some?
Giz, ¿quieres?
Do you want some chicken?
¿Quieres pollo?
That's it, good buddy. Call it a night.
Esto es todo por hoy, amigo.
Can't you see? They're after you!
¿No lo ves? ¡Vienen por nosotros!
They're after all of us! Our wives, our children, everyone!
¡Por todos nosotros! ¡Nuestras mujeres, hijos!
They're here already! You're next!
¡Ya están aquí! ¡Son los próximos!
Mom, could you come up here, please?
Mamá, ¿puedes subir?
Then I want you to bring the vacuum cleaner upstairs for me.
Sube la aspiradora.
What are they?
¿Qué son?
Well, they're the mogwai, I guess.
Creo que los mogwai.
Except for Gizmo.
Excepto Gizmo.
Did you get them wet?
¿Los mojaste?
Did you feed them after midnight?
¿Comieron después de medianoche?
Well, I gave them some chicken.
Les di pollo.
But I made sure that it...
Pero me aseguré de...
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
No, no, no. Un momento.
I made sure...
Me aseguré...
What's going on here?
¿Qué pasa aquí?
What'd you say this was called?
¿Cómo dice que se llama esto?
A putrid stage?
¿Fase de crisantemo?
Pupal. Pupal stage.
Crisálida. Fase de crisálida.
Like a butterfly.
Como las mariposas.
Yeah, right.
Exacto.
This is a cocoon, and inside he's going through changes.
Esto es un capullo, dentro está sufriendo cambios.
Lots of changes.
Muchos cambios.
Like my mother.
Como mi madre.
No, that's different.
No, eso es diferente.
This is called a metamorphosis.
Esto se llama metamorfosis.
It's a change in form...
Es un cambio en la forma...
...and in appearance.
...y la apariencia.
No, I'm sure it works fine.
No, funciona bien.
I was just out on the back porch for a second.
Había salido un momento al porche.
The convention's great.
La convención es fantástica.
I said it's great!
¡Digo que es fantástica!
Actually, the competition's...
La competencia...
Sorry, miss.
Perdón, señorita.
The competition's a little more advanced than I expected.
La competencia es grande.
I was changing my oil. Some really neat things.
- Efectuando cambio de aceite. - Hay cosas geniales.
Oh, Rand.
Oh, Rand.
You've never been so far away on Christmas Eve before.
Nunca habías estado tan lejos en Nochebuena.
I know it's Christmas Eve.
Ya lo sé.
I'll do the best I can.
Haré lo que pueda.
All right. Bye-bye.
Está bien. Adiós.
All I could get for it was $36!
Sólo pude sacar 36$.
If there's anything I can do... But it's completely out of my hands.
Si pudiera hacer algo... Pero no está en mis manos.
I'll be delighted...
Estaría encantado de...
Hello, Gerald. I'm under such terrible pressure.
Hola, Gerald. Estoy bajo presión.
Why don't you just speak to Mrs. Deagle about it?
¿Por qué no habla con la Sra. Deagle?
Speak to Mrs. Deagle?
¿Hablar con la Sra. Deagle?
Mrs. Deagle!
¡Sra. Deagle!
Deposit this to my account.
Pon esto en mi cuenta.
Where's that psychotic canine?
¿Y ese perro psicópata?
Still hiding under the counter?
¿Escondido tras el mostrador?
No, I'm afraid he's on vacation.
No, está de vacaciones.
Better keep him behind locked doors, because if I catch him...
Tenlo bajo llave, porque si lo pillo...
...he's in for a slow death.
...sufrirá una muerte lenta.
Here's Mr. Bird's heart.
Éste es el corazón del Sr. Pájaro.
Small animals lose heat faster than large ones.
Los animales pequeños pierden antes el calor.
Their blood must circulate faster to keep their bodies warm.
La sangre va más rápida para mantenerlos calientes.
Now, in small birds...
El corazón...
...their hearts beat about 600 times per minute.
...les late a 600 veces por minuto.
Cats, 130.
El de los gatos, a 130.
Man, about 75...
El del hombre, a 75...
...and a big old elephant's heart, only 25 a minute.
...y el de un gran elefante, sólo a 25.
Hey, doc, you got a human heart?
Doctor, ¿tiene un corazón humano?
Has he got a human heart? Wait till you see this! Roll 10.
¿Que si tiene un corazón humano? ¡Ahora verá!
Okay, class. Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
Muy bien, chicos. Feliz Navidad, Feliz Navidad.
If any of you wanna bring me a present...
Si quieres traerme un regalo...
...a cassette deck wouldn't be bad.
...un radiocasette no estaría mal.
Of course, tickets to the Super Bowl would be very nice.
Entradas para la Super Bowl también me gustarían.
Mr. Hanson, wait. Let me just talk to you for a second.
Sr. Hanson, espere. Quiero hablar con usted.
Bye.
Adiós.
It just hatched.
Ha salido del cascarón.
I'll be right there.
Voy enseguida.
Hey there.
Hola.
You remember me?
¿Te acuerdas de mí?
Remember me, don't you?
¿No?
I went and got you...
Fui a buscarte...
...a candy bar.
...un chocolate.
I thought you might be hungry.
Pensé que tendrías hambre.
You hungry?
¿Tienes hambre?
You should try one of these.
Deberías probarla.
Hey there.
Toma.
Come here. Don't be afraid. There's no reason to be afraid.
Ven aquí. No tengas miedo. No hay nada que temer.
Where'd you go?
¿Adónde vas?
Where are you? I know you're in there.
No te escondas. Sé que estás ahí.
I know you're under there.
Sé que estás ahí debajo.
Come on, now.
Ven aquí.
You're not still angry about that little blood test, are you?
¿No estarás enfadado aún por el análisis de sangre?
Come on out. Take a bite. Let me see you.
Sal. Dale un bocado. Deja que te vea.
I just wanna see you.
Sólo quiero verte.
You try some of this now. I know you gotta be hungry.
Prueba esto. Seguro que estás hambriento.
There now. Don't you feel better?
Eso es. ¿No te sientes mejor?
Gizmo ca-ca!
¡Gizmo pumba!
Billy, are you okay? Where are you?
Billy, ¿estás bien? ¿Dónde estás?
Mom, they hatched. Get out of the house.
Mamá, han salido del capullo. Vete de la casa.
Phone home. Ca-ca!
¡Pumba!
Get out of my kitchen!
¡Fuera de mi cocina!
Neat!
¡Genial!
- Are you all right? - I think so.
- ¿Estás bien? - Creo que sí.
Mom, it's Stripe!
¡Mamá, es Mechón!
- Should I get it? - Yeah, go ahead and get it.
¿Abro?
Oh, I didn't mean that.
Perdona.
Hello, Dr. Molinaro. Can we come in?
Hola, Dr. Molinaro. ¿Podemos pasar?
My mom's had a bit of an accident.
Mi madre ha tenido un accidente.
Be careful!
¡Ten cuidado!
What happened?
¿Qué ha pasado?
Giz?
¿Giz?
Bright light! Bright light!
¡Luz brillante!
Come here.
Ven aquí.
They almost got you, huh?
Casi te atrapan, ¿eh?
The question is totally without meaning.
La pregunta carece de sentido.
Pardon me, sir. Stuff.
Disculpe, señor.
Thick and heavy.
Grueso y pesado.
Would 60 gallons be sufficient?
¿Bastarían 270 litros?
I rarely use it myself, sir. It promotes rust.
No lo suelo utilizar, señor. Provoca oxidación.
Don't worry, Giz, we'll find him.
Tranquilo, lo encontraremos.
Gremlins, huh?
Gremlins, ¿eh?
Little monsters. - Right.
- Pequeños monstruos. - Eso es.
- Hundreds of them? - I'm not sure. Maybe thousands.
¿Centenares?
Look, I know it sounds crazy. I know it does.
Sé que parece una locura. Lo es.
But in a matter of hours, this town's gonna be a disaster area.
Pero en cuestión de horas, se producirá una catástrofe.
You've got to warn people!
¡Hay que avisar a la gente!
- You think this kid is drunk? - No, but you are.
- ¿Crees que está borracho? - No, pero tú sí.
I am not drunk!
¡No lo estoy!
Tell me something. Where do these little gremlins come from?
Dime una cosa. ¿De dónde han salido esos gremlins?
All right.
Veamos.
My father gave me one as a present.
Mi padre me regaló uno.
Does your father always give you vicious little monsters?
¿Tu padre suele regalarte monstritos perversos?
No, they don't start out vicious at first!
¡No, al principio no son perversos!
Of course not.
Claro que no.
They don't! They look like this.
¡En serio! Son así.
Could you dim the lights?
¿Puede bajar la luz?
Sure.
Claro.
Go ahead, Brent. Dim the lights.
Anda, Brent. Baja la luz.
Gusto!
¡Vamos!
Right, Murray?
¿Verdad, Murray?
Sheila, will you quit messing with the TV?
Sheila, deja de cambiar los canales.
You have the thingy.
El mando lo tienes tú.
Goddamn foreign TV.
Maldita tele extranjera.
We should've got a Zenith!
¡Te dije que compráramos un Zenith!
Foreigners.
Extranjeros.
I can't get a damn thing on this!
¡No se ve nada!
Where are you going?
¿Adónde vas?
I'm gonna check the antenna. Maybe the damn thing blew down.
A mirar la antena. A lo mejor se ha caído.
Be careful, dear.
Ten cuidado, cariño.
What the hell is that?
¿Qué demonios es eso?
- It's them! - You're crazy!
- ¡Son ellos! - ¡Estás loco!
There's a real gremlin in my cab!
¡Un gremlin en mi excavadora!
Hello, Anderson. Wanna mail something, do you?
Hola, Anderson. ¿Vas a echar una carta?
Just a last-minute package, Father.
Un paquete, Padre.
Be my guest.
Adelante.
That's strange.
¿Qué pasa?
Patriotic little fellow, ain't he?
¡Qué patriótico!
Waving the flag and everything.
Cómo mueve la bandera.
Be careful, Frank! He might tear your arm off.
¡Cuidado, Frank! Puede arrancarte el brazo.
You want me to put the cuffs on him?
¿Le pongo las esposas?
Tell me. How come a cute guy like this...
Dime. ¿Cómo puede una monada así...
...can turn into a thousand ugly monsters?
...convertirse en mil monstruos?
You see, this is before it enters the pupal stage.
Son así antes de la fase de la crisálida.
It multiplies with water.
Además, se multiplican con el agua.
Get the kid some water. I wouldn't do that.
- Tráele agua. - Yo no haría eso.
Sheriff's office.
Oficina del Sheriff.
Yeah, speaking.
Sí, al habla.
What?
¿Qué?
Yeah, sure, we'll be right over.
Enseguida vamos.
What happened?
¿Qué pasa?
The Futtermans.
Los Futterman.
Something about a snowplow. A freak accident.
Un problema con su excavadora. Un accidente raro.
It's the creatures!
¡Son las criaturas!
The creatures are making it look like an accident!
¡Ellas hacen que parezca un accidente!
Will you listen to me?
Escúchame.
You listen to me, kid!
¡Escúchame, muchacho!
Go on home, take little Gizmo...
Ve a casa, llévate a Gizmo...
...sit by the fireplace and open your Christmas presents.
...siéntate junto al fuego y abre los regalos.
Attaboy.
Buen chico.
Let me drive. No, you're drunk.
- Déjame conducir. - No.
You always drive!
¡Siempre conduces tú!
Because I'm the sheriff, asshole.
Porque soy el Sheriff, imbécil.
Kopeck, you stop that, you bad kitty!
¡Kopeck, para ya, gatito malo!
Kopeck's a bad kitty.
Kopeck es un gatito malo.
Ruble's a good little kitty.
Ruble es una buena gatita.
We'll find you something to eat. She's a good kitty.
Te daré algo de comer. Gatita buena.
Here we go. Here we go. Come on.
Vamos, vamos.
All right, you stop that!
¡Está bien, para ya!
Stop it!
¡Para!
Mean kitty, you start eating before everybody gets here.
Quieres empezar antes que los demás.
Come on, Dollar Bill.
Vamos, Dollar Bill.
Yes, here we go, Dollar Bill.
Está bien, Dollar Bill.
Mommy'll fix you something good to eat.
Mamá te va a preparar algo bueno.
Everybody here?
¿Están todos?
All right, let go of Mommy's coat.
Deja la chaqueta de mamá.
Here.
Aquí.
Christmas carolers.
Villancicos.
I hate Christmas carolers.
Odio los villancicos.
Screechy-voiced little glue-sniffers.
Esos zarrapastrosos con voz chillona.
I warned you brats!
¡Se los advertí mocosos!
What are they?
¿Qué son?
They're here!
¡Están aquí!
They've come for me! They've come!
¡Han venido por mí! ¡Han venido!
I'm not ready.
Aún no estoy lista.
I'm not ready yet. I'm not ready!
Aún no estoy preparada. ¡No estoy preparada!
My God, Frye!
¡Dios mío, Frye!
That was Mrs. Deagle.
Es la Sra. Deagle.
Get them off! Get them off! Help me!
¡Fuera! ¡Fuera! ¡Socorro!
That's Dave Myers. He does Santa every year.
Es Dave Myers. El que hace de Papá Noel.
What the hell is he doing now?
¿Qué demonios está haciendo?
What's that stuff he's got all over him?
¿Qué es eso que tiene encima?
Frank, I really think we should go now.
Frank, creo que deberíamos irnos.
Start the car. I'd really like to go back to the station.
Arranca. Quiero volver a la comisaría.
Please!
¡Por favor!
Jesus, Frank!
¡Por Dios, Frank!
What the hell are those things?
¿Qué diablos es eso?
It's Christmas. What the hell's going on?
Estamos en Navidad. ¿Qué demonios pasa?
Shut up, will you?!
Cállate, ¿está bien?
I don't believe it.
No puedo creerlo.
You're on with Rockin' Ricky! Go!
¡Sigues con Rockin' Ricky!
Hi, my name's Pete.
Hola, me llamo Pete.
These green guys are running around wrecking things.
Unos seres verdes están arrasando con todo.
This is Christmas, not Halloween!
¡Esto es Navidad, no Halloween!
Listen, gang.
Escúchenme, chicos.
Rockin' Ricky's getting fed up with this Orson Welles crap!
¡Estoy harto de ese cuento a lo Orson Welles!
What's that? Kitty, what's that? Some of Rockin' Ricky fans?
¿Qué es eso?
You're not a Rockin' Ricky fan!
¡Tú no eres fan de Rockin' Ricky!
Sir, I notice that you're a smoker.
Señor, veo que es usted fumador.
I notice that you're a smoker. I see the cigarettes.
Veo que es fumador. Lo digo por los cigarrillos.
I noticed, here, this broken ashtray.
Y por el cenicero roto.
It's very fortunate that I happened to come by.
Tiene suerte de que esté aquí.
Let me introduce myself. My name's Randall Peltzer. I'm an inventor.
Me presento. Me llamo Randall Peltzer. Soy inventor.
"Fantastic Ideas for a Fantastic World. " I make the illogical logical.
"Ideas Geniales para un Mundo genial". Hago lo ilógico, lógico.
I have something here that I think you might be interested in.
Tengo algo que puede interesarle.
Yes, sir, I do.
De verdad.
This is...
Esto es...
...the Peltzer Smokeless Ashtray.
...el Cenicero Absorbente Peltzer.
I think this can solve your problem here, sir.
Esto puede resolver sus problemas, señor.
Please don't bite me!
¡Por favor, no me muerdas!
Wait a minute.
Un momento.
You all right?
¿Estás bien?
Let's get out of here!
¡Salgamos de aquí!
What's that?
¿Qué es eso?
Don't worry. He's with me. He's not one of them.
No te preocupes. No es uno de ellos.
What's wrong? Why isn't the car starting?
¿Qué ocurre? ¿Por qué no arranca?
We're gonna have to make a run for it, okay?
Tendremos que correr, ¿de acuerdo?
One, two, three!
¡Uno, dos, tres!
They've been here too.
Han pasado por aquí.
What are these things? Where do they come from?
¿Qué son? ¿De dónde han salido?
They're gremlins, Kate.
Son gremlins, Kate.
Just like Mr. Futterman said.
Como los que dijo el Sr. Futterman.
Now I have another reason to hate Christmas.
Una razón más para odiar la Navidad.
What are you talking about?
¿Qué quieres decir?
The worst thing that ever happened to me was on Christmas.
Lo peor que me ha pasado en mi vida ocurrió en Navidad.
Oh, God. It was so horrible.
Dios mío. Fue tan horrible.
It was Christmas Eve.
Era Nochebuena.
I was 9 years old.
Tenía 9 años.
Me and Mom were decorating the tree...
Mi madre y yo decorábamos el árbol...
...waiting for Dad to come home from work.
...y esperábamos a papá.
A couple hours went by.
Pasaron un par de horas.
Dad wasn't home.
Y papá no volvía.
So Mom called the office. No answer.
Mamá llamó a su oficina. Nadie respondió.
Christmas Day came and went, and still nothing.
Llegó el día de Navidad, y nada.
So the police began a search.
La policía inició la búsqueda.
Four or five days went by.
Pasaron cuatro o cinco días.
Neither one of us could eat or sleep.
No podíamos comer ni dormir.
Everything was falling apart.
Todo se nos venía encima.
It was snowing outside.
Afuera nevaba.
The house was freezing, so I went to try to light up the fire.
La casa estaba fría, así que fui a encender el fuego.
That's when I noticed the smell.
Fue cuando noté el olor.
The firemen came and broke through the chimney top.
Vinieron los bomberos y abrieron la chimenea.
And me and Mom were expecting them to pull out a dead cat or a bird.
Mamá y yo esperábamos encontrar un gato o un pájaro muerto.
And instead they pulled out my father.
Pero sacaron a mi padre.
He was dressed in a Santa Claus suit.
Iba vestido de Papá Noel.
He'd been climbing down the chimney...
Quiso bajar por la chimenea...
...his arms loaded with presents.
...con los brazos llenos de regalos.
He was gonna surprise us.
Para darnos una sorpresa.
He slipped and broke his neck. He died instantly.
Resbaló y se rompió el cuello. Murió en el acto.
And that's how I found out there was no Santa Claus.
Así me enteré de que Papá Noel no existía.
Don't worry about that smoke. It'll stop. It's guaranteed.
No se preocupe por el humo. Desaparece. Garantizado.
Barney, shut up!
Barney, ¡cállate!
Don't start with me. I got a long way to go.
Para. Nos queda mucho camino.
Shut up!
¡Calla!
Where did they all go?
¿Dónde estarán?
It'll be light soon.
Va a amanecer.
I bet they're all together someplace dark.
Estarán en algún sitio oscuro.
Mogwai!
¡Mogwai!
They're inside.
Están aquí dentro.
All of them?
¿Todos?
Milk Duds.
Silencio.
What are they doing?
¿Qué hacen?
They're watching Snow White.
Están viendo Blancanieves.
And they love it.
Y les encanta.
Where's the boiler room?
¿Dónde están las calderas?
It's in the back of the theater.
En la parte de atrás.
Down there.
Allí debajo.
Milk Duds.
Silencio.
Cover your mouth. Don't breathe any gas.
Tápate la boca. No respires gas.
Go.
Vamos.
- Hurry up! - Move, Katie! Watch out!
¡Rápido!
Come on!
¡Vamos!
In the department store.
En el Centro Comercial.
Stripe!
¡Mechón!
That's Stripe. He's the leader.
Es Mechón. El jefe.
If he gets to water, it'll start all over again.
Si se moja, todo volverá a empezar.
Take Giz, go back and try and find some kind of light switch.
Toma a Giz, y busca algún interruptor de la luz.
Careful, Billy.
Ten cuidado, Billy.
Ward is your snowplow headquarters.
El quitanieves...
Attention, Christmas shoppers.
Atención, señores clientes.
Saturday morning at 8:30, we'll have Santa Claus for all the kiddies.
El sábado por la mañana a las 8:30, tendremos aquí a Papá Noel.
We have the Kingston Falls...
Los Kingston Falls...
Attention, shoppers.
Atención, señores clientes.
Light bright!
¡Luz brillante!
Bye-bye.
Adiós.
It takes a certain kind of guy.
...Un hombre especial.
And that guy needs a certain kind of dame.
Y ese hombre necesita una mujer especial.
Water!
¡Agua!
Gun!
¡Pistola!
It's been a rough night for Rockin' Ricky...
Ha sido una dura noche para Rockin' Ricky...
...but he's still on the air!
...pero sigue en el aire.
The Marines are standing by with fire hoses.
Los Marines tienen preparadas mangueras.
Gizmo ca-ca!
¡Gizmo pumba!
Light bright! Light bright!
¡Luz brillante! ¡Luz brillante!
What the hell is that?
¿Qué demonios es eso?
Your scarf.
Déjame tu bufanda.
We switch to a report...
Pasamos a informar...
...from the scene of the Christmas Eve riots.
...de los disturbios de Nochebuena.
This is Lew Landers, WDHB's Action Central News...
Les habla Lew Landers, Noticias de WDHB...
...at the site of Dorry's Tavern...
...desde el bar de Dorry...
...or what used to be Dorry's Tavern, in Kingston Falls...
...o lo que queda de él, en Kingston Falls...
...where officials blame...
...las autoridades culpan...
...mass hysteria for the escalating series of unexplained...
...a la histeria colectiva de la ola de inexplicables...
...accidents, fires and explosions that rocked this once-peaceful town...
...accidentes, incendios y explosiones que han azotado a esta ciudad...
...on Christmas Eve.
...en Nochebuena.
The bizarre demise of Mrs. Ruby Deagle, widow...
La extraña muerte de la Sra. Deagle, viuda...
...of convicted stock-swindler Donald Deagle...
...del especulador convicto Donald Deagle...
Don't chew that.
No muerdas esto.
Don't chew.
No lo muerdas.
I bet he'd like some chicken soup.
¿Te apetece una sopa de pollo?
Honey, this is the gentleman who sold me the mogwai.
Cariño, éste es el caballero que me vendió el mogwai.
"Sold. " An interesting choice of words.
"Vendió". Interesante elección de palabra.
Conflicting eyewitness reports concerning "little green men"...
Testimonios acerca de los "hombrecitos verdes"...
You teach him to watch television?
¿Le enseñan a ver la televisión?
There was, I believe, a box.
Creo que había una caja.
Dad...
Papá...
Rand, your scarf.
Déjame tu bufanda.
I warned you.
Se lo advertí.
With mogwai comes much responsibility.
Mogwai conlleva mucha responsabilidad.
But you didn't listen.
Pero no me escuchó.
And you see what happens.
Y ya ve lo que ha pasado.
I didn't mean it.
Fue sin querer.
You do with mogwai what your society...
Han hecho con Mogwai lo que su sociedad...
...has done with all of nature's gifts.
...ha hecho con los dones de la naturaleza.
You do not understand.
No entienden.
You are not ready.
No están preparados.
He has something to say to you.
Tiene algo que decirle.
You understand what he says when he speaks to you?
¿Entiende lo que dice cuando habla?
To hear, one has only to listen.
Para oír, sólo hay que escuchar.
Bye, Billy.
Adiós, Billy.
Perhaps someday you may be ready.
Quizá esté preparado algún día.
Until then, mogwai...
Hasta entonces, Mogwai...
...will be waiting.
...estará esperando.
Excuse me, sir.
Discúlpeme, señor.
Before you go, I wanted to tell you...
Antes de que se vaya...
...that I am truly sorry for what's happened.
...siento mucho lo ocurrido.
And if you would accept it, I'd like to...
Me gustaría que aceptara...
...give you this small token.
...este pequeño obsequio.
There's one other one. This is an invention of mine.
Es único. Un invento mío.
Smokeless Ashtray.
Cenicero Absorbente.
How did you know?
¿Cómo lo sabe?
Man at gas station tried to sell me.
Un hombre quiso vendérmelo en una gasolinera.
Latest word in technology.
El último grito en tecnología.
Very generous of you.
Muy generoso por su parte.
I'm sure it will come in handy.
Seguro que me irá bien.
Well, that's the story.
Bien, ésta era la historia.
So if your air conditioner goes on the fritz, your washing machine blows up...
Si su aire acondicionado se estropea, explota su lavadora...
...or your video recorder conks out...
...o su video falla...
...before you call the repairman...
...antes de llamar a un técnico...
...turn on the lights, check the closets and cupboards...
...encienda las luces, mire bien en los armarios...
...look under all the beds.
...debajo de las camas.
Because you never can tell.
Porque nunca se sabe.
There just might be a gremlin in your house.
Quizá tenga un gremlin en su casa.